Guide to the Lincoln Collection Sheet Music 1836-1878
University of Chicago Library
Lincoln Collection. Sheet Music
1836-1878
8 linear feet (4 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Lincoln Collection, Sheet Music contains sheet music relating to Abraham Lincoln, the Civil War, and the American nation in general during the nineteenth century. It forms a part of the William E. Barton Collection of Lincolniana.
Information on Use
Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Rev. William Eleazar Barton (1861-1930) The Rev. William Eleazar Barton (1861-1930) was one of the early twentieth century's most prominent writers and lecturers on the life of Abraham Lincoln. Born in Sublette, Illinois, in the same year Lincoln assumed the presidency, Barton grew up in an environment heavily influenced by reverence for Lincoln. After pursuing undergraduate studies at Berea College in Kentucky, Barton earned his divinity degree from the Oberlin Theological Seminary in 1890. He served parishes in Tennessee, Ohio, and Massachusetts before becoming the pastor of the First Congregational Church of Oak Park, Illinois, a position he held until his retirement in 1924. Four years later, Barton accepted an appointment as lecturer at Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, where he also organized and served as pastor of the Collegeside Congregational Church.
Barton's work as a writer produced a number of denominational manuals for church organization and a series of books presenting the wisdom and parables of a character he named Safed the Sage. For the last ten years of his life, however, Barton was best known to the public as a prolific author and lecturer on Abraham Lincoln. His publications about Lincoln included The Soul of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Paternity of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Life of Abraham Lincoln (1925), The Great and Good Man (1927), The Women Lincoln Loved (1927), and The Lincoln of the Biographers (1930).
In the course of compiling material for his writings and talks, Barton visited Lincoln sites in Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois; interviewed surviving Lincoln relatives and acquaintances; and traveled as far as California and England to collect information and conduct genealogical research on the ancestry of the Lincoln family. While acquiring a large collection of books, periodicals, pamphlets, manuscripts, and ephemera related to Lincoln and the Civil War era, Barton also purchased privately or at auction historical materials amassed by other Lincoln collectors such as John E. Burton and Osborn H. Oldroyd.
Scope Note
The Lincoln Collection Sheet Music has been arranged into four series: Series I, Civil War Era Sheet Music, Series II, Lincoln Sheet Music, and Series III, Nineteenth Century American Sheet Music, and Series IV, Civil War Song Sheets. The sheet music in these various series formed part of William E. Barton’s extensive collection of Lincolniana. Little is known about the origin of the music but some were originally inventoried and reviewed against standard resources.
Series I, Civil War Era Sheet Music, consists of sheet music materials which fall under the categorical theme of Civil War Era. It is arranged alphabetically by lyricist or composer. This series is mainly comprised of soldier and funeral marches, but also housed here are scores that commemorate battles and fallen soldiers such as E.E. Ellsworth.
Series II, Lincoln Sheet Music, consists of memorial songs, dirges, and funeral marches in sorrow for the loss of Abraham Lincoln. In this series are also songs in support of Lincoln and the conquest of the Civil War and those in general commemoration to his life as chief of the nation. The reference for this collection: Warren, Louis A. Lincoln Sheet Music. Check List. Fort Wayne, Ind. Lincolniana Publishers. 1940.
Series III: Nineteenth Century American Sheet Music contains material which offer a general survey of popular music from 1851-1878. The types of musical compositions represented here include polkas, mazurkas, schottisches, quicksteps, waltzes, marches, and practice pieces for the piano and piano-forte with variations provide. Also featured here at the end of the collection are a number of musical pieces from the composer Stephen C. Foster; among them is one of his most notable pieces titled “Beautiful Dreamer.”
Series IV, Civil War Song Sheets, contains song sheets with the lyrics of pieces encouraging the support of the Union and dirges in memorial of Lincoln’s death. They are arranged and described according to the entry in: WOLF, Edwin, 2nd. American Song Sheets, Slip Ballads, and Poetical Broadsides 1850-1870. A catalogue of the Collection of the Library Company of Philadelphia. Philadelphia: The Library Company of Philadelphia. 1963.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Barton, William Eleazar, 1861-1930; Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Collectors and collecting; Music -- United States -- 19th century
INVENTORY
- Series I: Civil War Era Sheet Music
  - Bliss, P. P., words & music, HOLD THE FORT! to Major D. W. Whittle. Chicago, Ill.... Song and Chorus. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1870. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clark, James G., THE COPPERHEAD OF 1864. THE CHICAGO COPPERHEAD, AND THE COPPERHEAD OF 1865. New York. Horace Waters. c1864. piano & vocal 4 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Griggin, G. W. H., words & melody. Arranged for the piano by E. H. F., POOR OLD SLAVE. Respectfully dedicated to S. B. Ball esq. the celebrated tenor of Ordway Aeolian Vocalists. Boston. G. P. Reed & Co. c1851. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hempsted, H. N., composer, FOUR POPULAR MARCHES AND QUICKSTEPS: #1 MILWAUKEE LIGHT GUARD QUICKSTEP. Milwaukee. H. N. Hempsted. c1866. Piano 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Herbert, G. R., PRESIDENT JOHNSON'S GRAND UNION MARCH. For the piano. Chicago. Lyon & Healy. c1865. Piano 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Himmel,. music composed by... written by Walter Maurice., BATTLE PRAYER. Boston. Russel & Tolman. n.d. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lawrence, Phillip H., BEATTY'S GRAND WELCOME MARCH... Reception of Hon. Daniel F. Beatty, Mayor of Washington, New Jersey... upon his return from Europe, Sept. 30, 1878. No publisher listed. (1878). Piano 6 p. Illus. cover. Empire Lithograph & Engraving Co. N. Y. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - McIntosh, Major E. W., words and music, DIXIE'S SUNNYLAND. We Chose Death Rather than Dishonor. Chicago. Lyon & Healy. c1887. piano & vocal 4 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Martin, T. J., author of "Persifer Smith's March", GEN. SIGEL'S GRAND MARCH. Cleveland. S. Brainard & Son. c1863. Piano. 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Root, George F., JUST BEFORE THE BATTLE, MOTHER. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1863. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Root, George F., JUST BEFORE THE BATTLE MOTHER. Song and Chorus. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1863. piano & vocal. 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Root, George F., TRAMP! TRAMP! TRAMP! THE PRISONER'S HOPE. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1861. piano & vocal 6 p., Illus. cover. Lithograph by Copcutt-Williams. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Root, George F. words by Rev. T. Newton Jones, WITHIN THE SOUND OF THE ENEMY'S GUNS. A descriptive song. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1862. piano & vocal 8 p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Skedaddles", FLOYD'S RETREAT FROM FORT DONELSON. With a running description of the battle. St. Louis. A. C. Peters & Bros. - J. L. Peters & Bro. c1862. piano & vocal 8 p. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Towne, T. Martin, of the continental vocalists., CONCERT GEMS. THE UNION LEAGUE. Chicago. H. M. Higgins. c1863. piano & vocal quartette 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tucker, music words by E. Bowers, DEAR MOTHER I'VE COME HOME TO DIE. Song and Chorus. New York. Firth, Son & Co. c1863. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Turner, J. W. arranged for piano by..., GOV. LINCOLN'S FUNERAL MARCH. To the memory of the late Gov. Levi Lincoln of Massachusetts. Boston. G. D. Russell & Co. c1868. Piano 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Unknown, BRECKINRIDGE SCHOTTISCHE. Dedicated to the Hon. John C. Breckinridge. Philadelphia Lee & Walker n.d. cover only Illus. cover. Lithograph by T. Sinclairs. Philadelphia (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Unknown, GLORY HALLELUJAH. The popular refrain of... as sung by the Federal Volunteers throughout the Union. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1861. piano & vocal 4 p. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Unknown, THE UNION "BELL" POLKA. Dedicated to the Hon. John Bell of Tenn. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. n.d. cover only Illus. cover. lithograph by T. Sinclairs. Philadelphia (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Warren, George William, A REQUIEM. In memory of Ellsworth. New York. Firth, Pond & Co. c1861. piano 8 p., Illus. cover. Lithograph by Sarony, Major & Knapp (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Whiting, S. K., FATHER'S COME HOME. Root's & Cady's Vocal Quartets. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1865. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Work, Henry C., LITTLE MAJOR. Dedicated to Miss Lucy A. Parker, Greenwich Village, Massachusetts. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1862. piano & vocal 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Work, Henry Clay, RING THE BELL, WATCHMAN! Chicago. Root & Cady. c1865 piano & vocal 4 p. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series II: Lincoln Sheet Music
  - Archer, C., REST, NOBLE CHIEFTAIN. Song on the Death of President Lincoln. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. c1865. piano & vocal 6 p., Warren no. 6. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Berneker, F. words by Wm. T. Rice, LINCOLN, PRIDE OF SPRINGFIELD, ILLINOIS. Springfield, Ill. Wm. T. Rice. c1927. piano & vocal 6 p., Warren no. 20. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bishop, T. Brigham, ABRAHAM THE GREAT AND GENL. GRANT HIS MATE. Campaign song for 1864. Cincinnati. John Church Jr. c1864. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 22. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bradbury, William B., "HOLD ON ABRAHAM". To the President of the United States... Being a Response of Uncle Sam's Boys to the Call for 'Three Hundred Thousand More',... sung... by Wood's Minstrels. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. c1863. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 27. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Delancy, Alfred, DIRGE. Sung at the Consecration of the Soldier's Cemetery at Gettysburg. (Nov. 19th, 1863), Gettysburg, Pa. published by the surviving daughters of Martha (martin) Wills, the Misses, Wills. n.d. piano & four voices, 6 p., photograph pasted on cover Warren no. 72. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dresser, Paul, GIVE US JUST ANOTHER LINCOLN. New York. Howley, Haviland. c1900 piano & vocal, 8 p., Illus. cover. color., Warren no. 75. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Emerson, L. O. poetry by William Cullen Bryant (sic), WE ARE COMING FATHER ABR'AM 300, 000 MORE. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c(1862) piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 81. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Everest, C., TOLL THE BELL MOURNFULLY. Written and composed on the death of President Abraham Lincoln. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 90. variant 1. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gilmore, P. S., WE ARE COMING FATHER ABRAAM, THREE HUNDRED THOUSAND MORE. Boston. Russell & Patee. c1862. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 105. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gougler, Isaiah W., LINCOLN'S GRAVE. New York. Wm. A. Pond U Co. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 110. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Irving, A. B., WE ARE COMING FATHER ABRAHAM or THREE HUNDRED THOUSAND MORE. Inscribed to our Volunteers. Chicago. H. M. Higgins. c1862. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 137. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mack, E., PRESIDENT LINCOLN'S FUNERAL MARCH. Respectfully dedicated to the People of the United States. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. c1865. Piano, 6 p., Illus. cover. Lithograph by T. Sinclairs. Philadelphia, Warren no. 169. variant 1. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mack, E., PRESIDENT LINCOLN'S FUNERAL MARCH. Respectfully dedicated to the People of the United States. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. c1865. Piano, 6 p., Illus. cover. Lithograph by T. Sinclairs. Philadelphia, Warren no. 169. variant 2. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Meyer, Henry, GRAND FUNERAL MARCH. To the memory of Abraham Lincoln. New York. Wm. A. Pond. c1865. cover only Illus. cover. Lithograph of Major & Knapp. New York., Warren no. 175. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Parkhurst, Mrs. E. A., FUNERAL MARCH. To the memory of Abraham Lincoln... New York. Horace Waters. c1865. Piano, 6 p., Warren no. 196. variant 1. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Parks, J. A. words by S. E. Kiser, LINCOLN. York, Nebraska. The J. A. Parks Co. c1914. piano & four voices, 8 p., Warren no. 197. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Porter, J. W., THE MARTYRED PATRIOT. Grand Funeral March Performed on the Reception of the Remains of our Beloved President Abraham Lincoln at Philadelphia. April 22, 1865. Philadelphia J. Marsh. c1865. Piano, 6 p., Warren no. 207. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Robjohn, W. J., ABRAHAM LINCOLN'S FUNERAL MARCH. Dedicated to the People of the United States. Detroit. J. Henry Whittemore. c1865. Piano, 6 p., Warren no. 216. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Sambo", YEAR OF JUBILEE or KINGDOM HAS COME. Chicago. H. M. Higgins. c1862. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 227. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Thomas, J. R. words by Geo. Cooper, OUR NOBLE CHIEF HAS PASSED AWAY. Elegy on the Death of Abraham Lincoln. New York. Wm. A. Pond. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 253. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Thompson, H. S., A NATION MOURNS HER CHIEF. St. Louis. Balmer & Weber. c1865. piano & vocal 6 p., Warren no. 254. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Turner, J. W. poetry by Miss M. J. Bishop, THE NATION'S HONORED DEAD. Monody on the Death of our Beloved President. Boston. C. C. Clapp & Co. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 262 (unlisted variant). (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Turner, J. W., A NATION WEEPS. Dirge on the death of Abraham Lincoln. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 266. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Turner, J. W., THE SOUR APPLE TREE. Or Jeff Davis' Last Ditch. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Illustrated cover. H. F. Greene, engraver, Warren no. 268. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Unknown (by a volunteer), 600,000 MORE. WE ARE COMING FATHER ABRAM! Cleveland. S. Brainard & Co. c1862. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 269. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Seventeenth edition of above, Warren no. 269 variant. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Wilmarth, F., REBELLION'S WEAK BACK. Boston. Russell & Petee. c1862. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 312. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Winner, Sep., HE'S GONE TO THE ARMS OF ABRAHAM. Songs of the Times arranged for the Piano-Forte. Philadelphia Sep. Winner. c1864. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 315 V. 3 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Winner, Sep. words by Alice Hawthorne, A NATION MOURNS HER MARTYR'D SON. In memory of Abraham Lincoln... Philadelphia Sep. Winner. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 316. V. 2. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Work, Henry C., "TIS FINISHED! or Sing Hallelujah. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1865. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 324. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Wurzel, G. F., DE DAY OB LIBERTY'S COMIN!. Wurzel's Liberty Song. Chicago. Root & Cady. c1862. piano & vocal, 6 p., Warren no. 327. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Zoeller, George, ENJOLRAS. The song of the patriot.. .Louisville. Faulds. c1865. piano & vocal, 8 p., Warren no. 329. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - McHarg, Wilson, music and words Richard Edwards, arranger, THE SPIRIT OF LINCOLN. manuscript piano & vocal, 3 p. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Salt, Enoch J., arranger H. Kugelman, words, DECORATION DAY. To the memory of Abraham Lincoln. Columbus, O. J. W. Fitzgerald. n.d. piano & vocal, 1 p., 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - PLEYELS HYMN, Sheets of music used at Lincoln's funeral. no publisher, n.d. vocal, 1 p., 5 copies plus 2 copies with "To Thee o Lord" on second page. Hand written note, undated. (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Series III: Nineteenth Century American Sheet Music
  - Baker, Jos. C., RENA BELL. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. c1867. piano & vocal, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Thomas, THE LAURA KEENE SCHOTTISCH. Dedicated to Miss Laura Keene. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. c1856 (1884 ed.) piano, 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Baumbach, Adolph, HOME, SWEET HOME. No. 12 in "Transcriptions Elegantes" Series. Cleveland. S. Brainard's Songs. c1862-1863. Piano, 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bishop, Henry R., HOME! SWEET HOME! Philadelphia Lee & Walker. n.d. piano & vocal, 6 p., Illustrated cover. T. Sinclairs' Lithograph (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dressler, William, NATALIE WALTZ. No. 7 in "Winter Evenings. A Collection of Selected Dances, Marches, Quicksteps, &c. " To James M. Deems, Esq., Prof. of Music in the Virginia University, Va. New York. William Hall & Son. c1852. Piano, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Grobe, Charles, HOPELESS NOT HEARTLESS. Brilliant Variations on "No One to Love". Aux Demoiselles Josie et Carrie Gould. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1861. Piano, 10 p. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hewitt, John H., THE FAIRMOUNT QUADRILLES. Dedicated to Miss Agnes Franciscus of Baltimore. Philadelphia John F. Nunns. c1836. piano & dance, 8 p., Illustrated cover. New York. Bufford's Lithograph (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Jungmann, A., HEIMWEH. "Flowers of Autumn" Series. Cleveland. S. Brainard & Co. n.d. piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kleber, H., SPIRIT POLKA. Dedicated to S. C. Foster, Esq. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. c1851. Piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Leduc, A., LA CHATELAINE FANTAISIE. "Lillies & Violets" Collection. Brooklyn. D. S. Holmes. n.d. piano, 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mack, E., GOOD EVENING MAZURKA. "Silver Sounds" Collection. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1868. Piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mack, E., SOLITUDE. To Miss Catherine A. Fryer. Philadelphia Lee & Walker. c1863. Piano, 8 p., Illustrated cover. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Maylath, H., NANCY LEE MARCH. Dedicated to the students of Jersey City High School. Jersey City, N. J. W. H. Ewald & Bros. c1878. Piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Millard, Harrison, THE WHIP-POOR WILL'S ECHO SONG. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1865. piano, guitar, & vocal, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Oesten, Theodore, HEARTLEAFLET (Herzblattchen). No. 3 in Wm. A. Pond & Co.'s No. 1 "White Roses" Series. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. n.d. piano, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Oesten, Theodore, IN SUMMER (Im Sommer). No. 5 in Wm. A. Pond & Co.'s No. 1 "White Roses" Series. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. n.d. piano, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Oesten, Theodore, IN THE SPRING (Im Fruhling). No. 1 in Wm. A. Pond & Co.'s No. 1 "White Roses" Series. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. n.d. piano, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Oesten, Theodore, A LITTLE STORY (Ein Marchen). No. 2 in Wm. A. Pond & Co.'s Standard Educational Series No. 1 "White Roses". New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. n.d. piano, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Peters, William C., OLD ROSIN, THE BOW. To Mr. Seymour Bowen. Fiftieth Edition. (Imprint blanked out, previously read as follows), Cincinnati. A. C. Peters & Bro. c1864., 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Spindler, F., GLOCKGHENSPIEL. From "Choice Compositions for the Pianoforte" Series. Cleveland. S. Brainard & Co. n.d. piano, 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Spindler, F., FRESH LIFE. From "Choice & Elegant Piano Forte Compositions.. ." Buffalo, N. Y. Cottier & Denton. n.d. piano, 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Spindler, F., SYLPH POLKA. From "Spindler's Gems" Collection. New York. S. T. Gordon & Son. Piano, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Stoddard, I. T., EVERGREEN WALTZ. Dedicated to Miss Roberta Archer. Baltimore. George Willig. c1852. Piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Strauss, Johann, KUNSTLER-LEBEN WALZER. (Artists Life). From "Strauss Dance Music" Series. Boston. Oliver Ditson & Co. c1872. Piano, 12 p., Illustrated cover. J. H. Bufford Lithograph Boston. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Vaas, A. J., CHICAGO CADETS QUICK STEP. Dedicated to the Cadets of Chicago. Chicago. H. M. Higgins. c1859. Piano, 10 p. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Verdi, G., WITH WHAT RAPTURE MY HEART IS BOUNDING. (I Masnadieri) New York. William Hall & Son. c1850. piano & vocal, 8 p., Illustrated cover. Lith. by Sarony of New York (picture of Jenny Lind) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Vilbre, Guillaume, HEAVENWARD! To Mrs. Geo. V. DeMotte. Boston. Oliver Ditson. c1866. Piano, 8 p., Illustrated cover. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Warren, Charles, FAIRYLAND WALTZ. Cleveland. S. Brainard. c1865, piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Wyman, Addison P., WOODLAND ECHOES. To Miss Sallie Brownson. Washington, Pa. Cleveland. S. Brainard's Sons. c1866. Piano, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Foster, Stephen, BEAUTIFUL DREAMER "One of the latest songs"... composed a short time before his death. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. 1864. piano & vocal, 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Foster, Stephen, GENTLE ANNIE. Foster's Melodies. No. 31... Ballad etc... New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1856. piano, guitar, & vocal, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Foster, Stephen, HARDTIMES COME AGAIN NO MORE. 25th ed. Foster's. Melodies No. 28. New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1854. piano, vocal & guitar, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Foster, Stephen, LULA IS GONE. Foster's Melodies No. 33. New York. Wm. A. Pond & Co. 1858. piano & vocal, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Foster, Stephen, MASSA'S IN THE COLD GROUND. To the Magnolias, Misses. Virginia T. Reddick, Anna Houston, Lidie Orme, & Lizzie Justice.. .New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1853. piano, 8 p., Arranged by Charles Grobe. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Foster, Stephen, OH BOYS CARRY ME ‘LONG. A Plantation Melody. New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1851. piano & vocal, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Foster, Stephen, MY OLD KENTUCKY HOME POLKA. Foster's American Melodies No. 21... sung by Christy's Minstrels, New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1853. piano & vocal, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Foster, Stephen, OLD DOG TRAY. Foster's Melodies #21. New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1853. piano & vocal, 6 p., Cover lists songs # 20 through # 27. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Foster, Stephen, PRETTY TUNES FOR LITTLE FOLKS. 14 Beautiful melodies by... Old Folks at Home. # 1. New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1858 (?). piano, 4 p., Arranged by James Bellak. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Foster, Stephen, PRETTY TUNES FOR LITTLE FOLKS. 14 Beautiful Melodies by... # 2 "My Old Kentucky Home". New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1858. Piano, 4 p., Arranged by James Bellak. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Foster, Stephen, WILLIE WE HAVE MISSED YOU. Foster's Melodies. New York. Firth, Pond & Co. 1854. piano & vocal, 8 p., Illustrated Cover. Lithograph by Sarony & Co. (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Series IV: Civil War Song Sheets
  - ABRAHAM'S DAUGHTER, "Oh! kind folks listen to my song, it is no idle story" (5 vs.) by Tony Emmett; cop: 1861. Sep. Winner, EDPa. Wolf #4 Variant b -- (Without Emmett's name); Sep. Winner's Music Store; publ. Auner. A-J border, 24.2 c 15.5 cm. Variant e -- Music obtained of Sep. Winner; print. J.H. Johnson; adv: Cards, Bill Two identical Liberty figures. 15.5 x 23.8 cm. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - THE AMERICAN VOLUNTEER, "I'm going to leave my native hills" (6 vs.) Air: The Girl I left behind me. Wolf #40 variant a -- From the Stars and Strips Songster, publ. Robert M. De Witt: publ. De Marsan, De Marsan eagle border, col. 25.7 x 17.0 cm. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - BATTLE CRY OF FREEDOM, OR, WE'LL RALLY ROUND THE FLAG BOYS., "Yes, we'll rally round the flag, boys, we'll rally once again" (4 vs. and chor.) by (George F. Root) Wolf #90 variant j -- Published and sung by James D. Gay; (with FLAG OF OUR UNION FOR EVER on recto.), T. o. border. 24.8 x 17.0 cm. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - FLAG OF OUR UNION FOREVER., "A song for our banner! the watchword recall" Wolf #651 variant g -- 3vs. and 3 5-line chors.; with "Forever" in two words; published by James D. Gay of Philadelphia, formerly a member of the Ringgold Artillery, Reading, Pa.; (with BATTLE CRY OF FREEDOM, OR WE'LL RALLY ROUND THE FLAG, BOYS on verso.) (Box 4, Folder 3)